[men grunting]
[man] Go, go!
[triumphant music playing on tape]
[men panting]
-Which way?
-Wait.
[rockets whistling]
[bursting]
-[gas hissing]
-[men coughing]
[men choking]
[Gordon] General, you were the ones
who let Walker operate
right under your noses.
Now you're telling me
she evaded capture?
[General on radio]
I understand your frustration.
[Gordon] Have you at least determined
why she did what she did?
[General] Not yet.
Look, bottom line,
Walker and Dorrance
are out of the picture.
What else is standing
in the way of reunification?
Nothing. I'm recommending
we begin the process immediately.
There have been a lot of promises
from across the river.
But unlike Walker, or whoever she is,
I have the authority to take action.
Unless something happens
to destabilize Gotham again,
this nightmare is about to end.
[Harvey]Think he's for real?
I'll believe it when it happens.
I take it your search party
didn't find Alfred.
[Harvey] Neither hide nor hair.
Pennyworth vanished five days ago.
It ain't looking good.
[Gordon] How's Bruce?
He's been pulling double shifts
on the search parties.
Kid's dead on his feet.
I want to search this area next.
There are whole blocks
of abandoned buildings.
I'll get a squad right on it.
Give me five minutes, I'll be ready.
No.
-You're not going out.
-No, Jim.
You need your rest.
I'm not cutting you out,
but I need you sharp,
not a liability.
I just don't understand
what could've happened.
Neither do I.
But I know that Alfred Pennyworth
can take care of himself.
I'll send for you if I hear anything.
-Kid's tough.
-Yeah.
In other goodish news,
Harper radioed.
-Her squad found something.
-What?
It's weird.
-[camera shutter clicks]
-[siren chirps]
[Harper] Four men.
Looks like they breathed in
some sort of chemical agent.
I'm thinking airborne.
And the Z's on their bodies?
Carved into them
before the time of death.
Check out the mustache.
[Gordon grunts]
Fake.
Seems like they escaped from here.
[Gordon] A film set.
[Harper] I said it was weird.
[Harvey] The Z's on their chest...
You think it could be Zsasz?
No, chemicals aren't really his MO.
Plus, I never figured Zsasz
for much of a cinephile.
But whoever it is,
if they have more of these chemicals
and the will to use them...
It's bye-bye, reunification.
We gotta stop 'em
before news reaches the mainland.
The Chessmen.
It's a gang that operates
out of The Narrows.
So what the hell is a Narrows
gang doing way up here?
I think we both know
someone we can ask.
-[footsteps approaching]
-[woman laughing]
Can you check on the fever in bed 12?
What's up, Doc?
Heard you were working here.
Interesting.
It's what I do, help people.
Speaking of which, I've got patients.
Oh, you wouldn't kick Jim's baby mama
to the curb, now, would you?
Whatever happened between
you and Jim,
it's none of my concern.
So, if you're here to gloat--
I'm here for medical assistance,
for my little nugget.
What do you say? Be my OB?
You can't be serious.
I know we've had our differences.
You tried to kill me, Barbara. Twice.
-That was years ago.
-[sighs]
There are other doctors here.
Not as good as you.
Look, whatever you think of me,
my child is innocent
and I want the best for it.
And in this place, that means you.
[sighs]
-Does Jim know you're here?
-This is none of his business.
[Gordon] Lee.
Jim.
Barbara.
You're interrupting.
Doctor-patient. Blow.
-I'm sorry. You're her doctor?
-[Lee] No. I don't know.
Maybe. What are you doing here?
Some bodies turned up.
They might have a Narrows connection.
-I wouldn't have come, but it's--
-It's important.
You two need to talk.
-I'll be outside.
-Uh, I'd rather not.
If you want me to your doctor,
you will talk to the baby's father.
Your first appointment is next week.
The nurse will give you
all your vitamins when you leave.
Deal?
Is she really the only one
you could find?
She's the best doctor
in this hellhole of a city.
-Not everything is about Jim Gordon.
-Pretty sure this one is.
Because we slept together? Yeah.
I only told you because
I felt you had a right to know,
but your involvement in this
ended the moment
-you put your pants back on.
-[scoffs]
What?
You don't think I'm fit
to be a mother?
What do you think?
Barbara.
[woman laughing]
[bats squeaking]
[man and woman laughing]
[whispering indistinctly]
[woman laughs]
Who are you?
Well, look who decided to join us.
Hello, champ.
[footsteps approaching]
[Alfred] Master Bruce!
Alfred, how did you...
Look at the state of you.
Haven't I told you about
rolling around in the muck?
Alfred, what's going on?
Who are these people?
[man] Whatever do you mean, Bruce?
We're your parents.
All right.
Well, let's get you spruced up.
After all, we have a guest.
Welcome home, Bruce.
Jeremiah. You're alive.
[laughing]
Well, you didn't think Selina could
kill me so easily, did you?
[laughing] I just had to
put you off my scent
until I could finalize my project.
Manners, Master Bruce!
Let's not be rude to our guest.
Especially when I come bearing gifts.
[Alfred] Oh, Mr. Jeremiah, a cake!
How exceedingly kind of you.
-Is it Italian meringue?
-Sure.
-[Alfred] Oh.
-Now, now, Bruce.
You come any closer
and I blow up Wayne Manor
with all of us inside of it.
I have a dozen more
of these, uh, Italian meringues
sprinkled all throughout the house.
What did you do to Alfred?
And who are these people?
I'm glad you asked.
Come. Come, come.
Mommy and Daddy dearest
were just an innocent couple
I kidnapped
based on bone structure and, um,
build.
Just a touch of plastic surgery,
andvoilà.
Waynes. [chuckles]
Alfred, I nabbed in the Green Zone.
They're hypnotized.
Well, I'm afraid there was
no room for improv in our script.
Today is a very important day, Bruce.
Just look at the way they're dressed.
It's the night
my parents were killed.
And I'm giving you the chance
to experience it all over again.
Why?
[Jeremiah] Isn't it obvious?
Bruce...
This... This was the most
important day of your life.
And I didn't get to be a part of it.
We need to rectify that.
Alfred, it's time for dinner.
Chop-chop, we're on
a very tight schedule.
[Alfred] Of course, Mr. Jeremiah.
[explosion]
That's zero for three.
[Penguin] Yes.
Seems the government was quite
thorough when they mined the river.
You didn't have a plan
to get off this rock
before you stole everyone's crap?
I was working on a plan.
[Selina] The river is mined.
Everything that flies out
gets blown from...
-the sky.
-What?
Jeremiah was digging
a tunnel under the river.
A tunnel? [scoffs] Really?
Do you have any better ideas?
Uh...
Didn't think so.
It's in the Dark Zone.
We should wait until night
to check it out.
Well, I was running out
of guinea pigs anyway.
Oh, look, he's swimming to shore.
[explosion]
[Lee] Are you sure you should be out
in The Narrows alone?
[Gordon] When the bridges fell,
this place descended into chaos.
I figure our best bet
of getting out in one piece
is to keep a low profile.
So all the work I did to make
The Narrows better was for nothing.
[clattering]
It's the Leopards,
the rivals of the Chessmen.
[indistinct chatter]
-About this Barbara thing...
-Jim, just don't.
No. It's important to me
that you understand.
Okay. So what are you gonna do?
I don't know, but it's my child, too.
Barbara seems to have
a difference in opinion.
Okay, people change.
You don't know her like I do.
You can say that again.
Look.
All clear.
The Chessmen moved around.
They used these as signals
for their members.
The rook's a compass needle.
North-northeast.
Let's go.
[cutlery clinking]
Alfred told me such great tidbits
about your childhood.
How you used to eat here,
in the kitchen,
when it was just you and the family.
My, how homey and intimate.
Grilled cheese and Branston pickle
sandwich, Mr. Jeremiah.
Master Bruce's favorite.
My influence, though Thomas did add
a dash of aioli for extra flair.
[laughing]
Oh. Come on, Bruce.
That's a weird favorite food
for a 12-year-old.
I'm playing your game.
Now, let Alfred and these people go.
They're innocent.
I'm sorry, Bruce. It's just...
It's very important to me that
I get every detail exactly right.
Speaking of which, the final touch.
What was it like...
losing your parents that night?
I lost my family, too, Bruce.
The wound still hasn't healed.
I think about it often.
None of this is real.
You're trying to manipulate me.
It will never be real.
But you are thinking
about that night...
and that's all I need.
I just want to be connected to you.
I offered for you
to be my best friend!
But I've realized
if we can't be friends,
then we can be connected
in other ways.
How?
You'll see...
in time.
Hmm.
I'm sorry to cut tonight short,
but your parents and I
have a very important date...
Jeremiah!
-...with destiny.
-[Bruce] Jeremiah!
You might want to find
your faithful butler and leave.
-Quickly.
-[device beeping]
Alfred!
[bell tolling in distance]
The signs lead this way.
Look at the smoke.
Someone re-started production.
[Lee] Oh, my God, Jim.
Look at all of this.
Come on.
Who's in charge here?
Ticktock, the chemical stock shall
give our Gotham an aftershock.
Ticktock, the chemical stock...
Shall give our Gotham an aftershock.
-They've been hypnotized
-It's Tetch.
[clapping]
My, my, what a thrill.
Jim Gordon...
and the woman he told me to kill.
It brings back memories.
That tea party was so long ago.
But now, to order
these men to attack my foe.
[Lee grunts]
All for one and one for all!
Ain't this a grand old ball?
[men grunting]
[Ecco] Yoo-hoo!
Ain't this
some game!
Give it to me again?
[sighs] Penguin has been stealing
everything in the city
that's not nailed down.
And now, he needs a way
of getting it off the island.
[Barbara] Hmm.
-And you're helping him?
-Well, that's what he thinks.
Barbara, Tabitha was my friend, too.
If anything, I wanna gut the twerp.
And take his loot.
Except you don't actually
have a way of out of Gotham.
I'll find one, tonight.
And I'll still need your help
moving the stuff.
We can get out of here, together.
Away from Jim Gordon?
Rich as Midas,
Penguin dead in a ditch?
Well, aren't we just
two single ladies and a baby,
about to kill
our sworn enemy together.
What?
It's just, you're pregnant.
-Don't even start.
-[gun clicks]
[Bruce] Alfred!
[beeping]
Alfred!
-We need to get outta here.
-Ah, Master Bruce.
I was just taking
a quiet moment to tidy up.
We need to go. The bombs.
-What bombs?
-These bombs!
No need for roughhousing, sir.
There has to be a way.
Alfred, you would do anything
to protect me, right?
Absolutely, sir.
There's a gas leak in the kitchen.
It's only a matter of time
before this whole place goes up.
A gas leak?
Where are your parents?
Where's our guests?
I've already warned them.
I know a way out. Come on!
[beeping rapidly]
-[Bruce] Alfred!
-[Alfred groans]
Alfred! [grunts]
[grunts] Oh, bloody hell.
Don't move.
-[panting]
-Do you, uh...
Oh, yeah. I remember everything.
Clear as day.
Let me tell you, if I ever see
that Jervis Tetch character again,
I'll stick that watch
so far up his...
His nose.
How about you?
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm all right.
The manor.
Don't you worry about that now, sir.
Come on, help me up.
[groaning]
Oh, your leg's hurt.
Yes. Well, it's not broken.
I thought I lost you.
Me?
Never, Master Bruce.
Go on.
You know where he's gonna be at.
Go.
If you're here,
Jeremiah must still be alive.
And if you're here, I'm guessing
you found our test subjects
all boiled and bubbled. [giggling]
-What's he planning?
-[Ecco shushing]
[Ecco] It's a surprise, don't you know?
A real killer.
[Tetch] Shall I hypnotize
our friends here
and have them slit
each other's necks?
[Ecco laughing] Nix.
Better check with the boss.
He might have other ideas.
[beeps]
I'm sorry I got you involved in this.
Don't be.
I knew what I was
getting myself into.
-I know, but, Lee...
-Jim...
Whatever you wanna tell me,
save it till we're outta here.
Fair enough.
I'm gonna find out
what Valeska's planning.
Hey, Tetch?
You know, it's funny...
I never figured you
for Jeremiah's errand boy.
Oh, Captain, no errands do I run.
This is simply a way
for me to have some fun.
[Lee scoffs] Tell yourself that.
What are you
when you would take away
your games and your rhymes?
Nothing but a second-rater
with a really silly hat.
Shut up.
[whispering indistinctly]
-[laughing]
-Beautiful. Beautiful.
[Tetch] Lee Thompkins,
you do intrigue me so.
First, you were a doctor.
Then The Narrows' queen.
-Tell me, please do.
-[watch ticking]
Are you running from your past
when you become someone new?
[lock clicking]
When I found Jeremiah,
he had a bunch of crazies
digging this tunnel for him.
[exhales] Well, that certainly
fills me with confidence.
Whoa. You hear that?
-[footsteps approaching]
-[gasps]
[panting]
-Alfred?
-[Alfred] Selina?
What are you doing here?
And with that?
I should ask you the same thing.
What's down that tunnel?
Well, it was Wayne Manor,
till Jeremiah blew it up.
He sealed the only way out of Gotham.
[stammering] No, Jeremiah is not alive.
I saw him die, right here.
Yeah, well, you're wrong.
We all were.
And now, he's embarked
on some madcap scheme,
where he's reenacting the night
Bruce's parent's were killed.
Where's Bruce?
He's gone after Jeremiah.
He could use your help.
-Wait!
-Don't you think
that because I did not kill Jeremiah
does not mean that I won't kill you!
Selina...
You killed my friend Tabitha.
You deserve to die.
[Alfred] Selina.
Just put the knife down.
Bruce needs you.
[gasping]
I suppose I should thank you.
Well, you could help me
to the Green Zone.
Of course, it's that way.
Jeremiah!
Show yourself!
[dramatic music playing]
[music continues]
Olé!
Hola,Bruce.
Well, here we are,
the theater where
your mommy and daddy took you to see
The Mark of Zorro.
Ha-ha!
I had heard you were obsessed
with this man as a child.
I wonder what it was that
intrigued you so.
Was it the fact that he struck fear
into the heart of his enemy?
En garde!
[grunting] Take that!
Vagabond.
-[grunting]
-[screaming]
[screams]
But...
Perhaps the movie
was a bit too effective.
Isn't this the part where
you became frightened?
When you asked your parents to leave?
I wonder what would have happened
if you hadn't done that.
If you had conquered your fear.
Maybe your parents
would still be alive.
Well, on to the last and final stop
down memory lane.
[Bruce] Stop!
Stop!
That's far enough, Bruce.
[Bruce] Jeremiah!
-You don't have to do this!
-But I...
I do.
See, I came to this realization.
I realized that no matter
what I did to bond us,
some random gunman in an alley
would be the man
who you were tied to the most.
The man you saw
when you closed your eyes.
I want to be the star of the show!
So, if I can't have you
as a brother bonded by love...
[gun cocks]
Then we'll just have
to be bonded by hatred.
And you think killing two people that
look like my parents will do that?
It won't.
Well, it's a good thing I already
put a bullet in both of
their fraudulent skulls.
Oh, you're confused.
You're wondering
if I already shot them,
then who's this lovely couple?
Thomas, Martha.
Why don't you turn around?
-Jim!
-[Jeremiah laughing]
I know!
See, over the course
of our little adventures,
fate brought to me James Gordon
and Leslie Thompkins,
and I thought to myself...
Why not...
Why not kill the man who you think of
as your second father figure?
And your dear, dear,
dear friend, Lee Thompkins.
And when I do,
finally you and I
will be bound together.
-[vehicle approaching]
-'Cause, you see...
[horn honking rhythmically]
Reunification with the mainland
hangs on by a thread.
Those fireworks go off,
and toxic chemicals
rain down onto the city
and the government [clicks tongue]
cuts us adrift for good.
[Bruce] Jeremiah...
don't.
Shhh.
And the pièce de résistance.
One last thing.
I had Jervis Tetch hypnotize them
so that they'll wake up
the moment these
beautiful pearls hit the ground.
I want you to see them realize
what I've done to them
as the life drains from their bodies.
Never forget.
This is all for you, Bruce.
No!
-[grunts]
-[punching]
[beeping]
Selina, the pearls!
-[Bruce groans]
-No!
[Jeremiah] Ecco! Now!
[beeping]
We need to stop the fireworks,
they're gonna--
I know.
You go after Jeremiah and Ecco.
I'll take the truck.
[beeping]
There's no way to stop them all.
Get to Harvey.
Warn the people in the Green Zone
to get to cover.
[Lee] Jim!
Jim!
Jeremiah!
Face me!
Here, Bruce!
[beeping rapidly]
[Bruce] Jeremiah!
This ends tonight.
No, no, Bruce. Now it begins. [laughs]
[both grunting]
[Jeremiah] Yes. [chuckles]
You feel it.
-The connection between us.
-[Bruce grunting]
[Jeremiah] You do.
Don't you?
Bruce, do you feel it?
Tell me you feel it. [groans]
You mean nothing to me.
Why don't you understand?
[both grunting]
You need me!
I'm the answer
to your life's question.
Without me, you're just a joke...
Without a punchline.
-[seagulls squawking]
-[bell tolling in distance]
After all this time,
you've come to me for help?
After allowing Strange
to put a chip into my brain?
Attempting to sell me out to Gordon?
And after naming a dog after me?
First of all,
I am very fond of that dog.
Secondly, I had Hugo Strange
save your life.
Thirdly, do you really think
I didn't have plans
to save you from Jim Gordon?
[laughing]
You always have an answer
for everything, don't you, Oswald?
We have been through
all of this before.
I've tried to kill you,
you've tried to kill me.
But here we are,
in this room, together.
It means fate
has different plans for us.
What are these plans?
Haven't you realized
what Gotham is yet?
It is no longer a city.
It is a prison.
And I think it's time we escaped.
You heard the news?
Everybody's talking about it.
Reunification isn't happening.
Word of the chemical spill
reached the mainland.
No action until the government
can determine if Gotham is safe.
I figure at least a couple of months.
You don't sound surprised.
'Cause I'm not.
Could've been much worse.
You stopped that.
[sighs] Every time I think
we're turning things around,
I look up, we're right back
where we started.
What were you about to say to me
when, uh, Tetch had us?
I don't know.
I guess I, uh, would have said...
what I said the last time
we saw each other.
I wish I could go back,
do things differently, better.
That feels like a long time ago.
Nothing's changed.
But it has, Jim.
That was a mistake.
A mistake?
Put yourself in my shoes.
After everything you said,
suddenly you're having a baby
with Barbara, of all people.
But it's not just that.
You talk about doing things
differently and I keep thinking,
what if we hadn't lost ours?
What're you doing here, Lee?
I don't know.
I know you've taken on so much and...
And I want
to be understanding, but...
you let me down, Jim.
I'm sorry.
What does that mean? For us?
I don't know.
Can't change the past, so I guess
we just have to live with it.
[scoffs]
[machine beeping]
[Selina] I can't believe
he's still alive.
[Bruce] They've been doing scans,
and he has no brain activity.
He's no longer a threat.
To either of us.
Thank you for coming to help me.
The night your parents were killed,
I should've done something.
Selina, you've done enough.
[thunder rumbling]
[Penguin] It's not much, but it's home.
[Barbara] I've been looking
through your treasure trove.
You've been a very naughty boy.
[Penguin] Barbara? How did you...
Selina.
Hmm.
She and I were gonna go
murder-halvsies
to get you back for Tabitha.
But it seems I will have to do
the dirty work myself, as usual.
[Nygma] Oh, my God.
You're pregnant.
How could you possibly know that?
Look at you!
She's glowing.
You're glowing.
How very observant of you.
Adieu, Oswald.
Wait! Come with us.
What?
Yes, I killed Tabitha.
You're angry. You want revenge.
But do you really want to raise
your child in a toxic waste war zone?
Come with us.
Are you telling me
you found a way out of Gotham?
Ed did.
It's a submarine.
A submarine?
It can track mines in the river
using sonar.
So, where's this submarine?
We have to build it.
Yeah, I'm gonna shoot you.
[whimpers]
God!
What is happening to me?
Perhaps--
[Barbara] Shut up!
That was a rhetorical question.
[sighs]
Fine. I won't shoot you,
for the sake of my child.
But I will never forgive you.
Of course. I understand.
[Barbara] Call me when it's done.
So, who's the lucky father?
[Barbara] Shut up!